I was accepted to Pepperdine University, and I came back to the same school that I attended to be a special ed assistant. And then I told them, "I want to be a teacher." And boy, they were like, "What? Why? Why would you want to do that?" So I began my teaching career at the exact same middle school that I attended, and I really wanted to try to save more kids who were just like me. And so every year, I share my background with my kids, because they need to know that everyone has a story, everyone has a struggle, and everyone needs help along the way. And I am going to be their help along the way. So as a rookie teacher, I created opportunity. I had a kid one day come into my class having been stabbed the night before. I was like, "You need to go to a hospital, the school nurse, something." He's like, "No, Miss, I'm not going. I need to be in class because I need to graduate." So he knew that I was not going to let him be a victim of his circumstance, but we were going to push forward and keep moving on. And this idea of creating a safe haven for our kids and getting to know exactly what they're going through, getting to know their families -- I wanted that, but I couldn't do it in a school with 1,600 kids, and teachers turning over year after year after year. How do you get to build those relationships? So we created a new school. And we created the San Fernando Institute for Applied Media. And we made sure that we were still attached to our school district for funding, for support. But with that, we were going to gain freedom: freedom to hire the teachers that we knew were going to be effective; freedom to control the curriculum so that we're not doing lesson 1.2 on page five, no; and freedom to control a budget, to spend money where it matters, not how a district or a state says you have to do it. We wanted those freedoms. But now, shifting an entire paradigm, it hasn't been an easy journey, nor is it even complete. But we had to do it. Our community deserved a new way of doing things. And as the very first pilot middle school in all of Los Angeles Unified School District, you better believe there was some opposition. And it was out of fear -- fear of, well, what if they get it wrong? Yeah, what if we get it wrong? But what if we get it right? And we did. So even though teachers were against it because we employ one-year contracts -- you can't teach, or you don't want to teach, you don't get to be at my school with my kids. (Applause) So in our third year, how did we do it? Well, we're making school worth coming to every day. We make our kids feel like they matter to us. We make our curriculum rigorous and relevant to them, and they use all the technology that they're used to. Laptops, computers, tablets -- you name it, they have it. Animation, software, moviemaking software, they have it all. And because we connect it to what they're doing — For example, they made public service announcements for the Cancer Society. These were played in the local trolley system. Teaching elements of persuasion, it doesn't get any more real than that. Our state test scores have gone up more than 80 points since we've become our own school. But it's taken all stakeholders, working together -- teachers and principals on one-year contracts, working over and above and beyond their contract hours without compensation. And it takes a school board member who is going to lobby for you and say, "Know, the district is trying to impose this, but you have the freedom to do otherwise." And it takes an active parent center who is not only there, showing a presence every day, but who is part of our governance, making decisions for their kids, our kids. Because why should our students have to go so far away from where they live? They deserve a quality school in their neighborhood, a school that they can be proud to say they attend, and a school that the community can be proud of as well, and they need teachers to fight for them every day and empower them to move beyond their circumstances. Because it's time that kids like me stop being the exception, and we become the norm. Thank you. (Applause)
Fui aceptada en la Universidad Pepperdine y volví a la misma escuela a la que asistí para ser asistente de educación especial. Y luego les dije: "Quiero ser profesora". Y decían: "¿Qué? ¿Por qué? ¿Por qué quieres hacer eso?" Así que empecé mi carrera docente en exactamente la misma escuela secundaria a la que asistí, y realmente quería tratar de salvar a más niños que estaban igual que yo. Y así, cada año, comparto mi experiencia con los niños, porque necesitan saber que todo el mundo tiene una historia, todo el mundo tiene una lucha, y todos necesitamos ayuda en el camino. Y yo voy a ser su ayuda en el camino. Como profesora novata creé oportunidades. Un día vino un niño a mi clase que fue apuñalado la noche anterior. Le dije: "Tienes que ir a un hospital, a la enfermera de la escuela, algo". Me dijo: "No, señorita, no iré. Tengo que estar en clase porque necesito graduarme". Sabía que yo no iba a dejar que él fuera una víctima de su circunstancia, pero nosotros íbamos a seguir adelante y seguir avanzando. Y esta idea de crear un refugio seguro para nuestros hijos y llegar a saber exactamente lo que están enfrentando, a conocer a sus familias... yo quería eso, pero no podía hacerlo en una escuela con 1600 alumnos, y profesores que cambian año, tras año, tras año. ¿Cómo se llegan a construir esas relaciones? Así que creamos una nueva escuela. Creamos el Instituto San Fernando de Medios Aplicados. Y nos aseguramos de estar todavía apegados a nuestro distrito escolar por financiamiento y apoyo. Pero con eso, ganaríamos libertad: libertad para contratar a los profesores que sabíamos serían efectivos; libertad de controlar el plan de estudios, para no tener que hacer la lección 1.2, de la página 5; y libertad para controlar el presupuesto, para gastar dinero donde más importa y no donde un distrito o estado dice que lo hagas. Queríamos esas libertades. Pero cambiar todo un paradigma no ha sido un camino fácil, y ni siquiera completo. Pero teníamos que hacerlo. Nuestra comunidad merecía una nueva forma de hacer las cosas. Y como la primera secundaria piloto de todo el Distrito Escolar Unificado de Los Ángeles, créanme que hubo oposición. Y fue por temor... temor a, bueno, ¿y si se equivocan? Sí, ¿y si nos equivocamos? ¿Y qué tal si acertamos? Y acertamos. Así que a pesar de que los profesores estaban en contra porque contratamos por año... si no puedes enseñar, o no quieres enseñar, no puedes estar en mi escuela con mis niños. (Aplausos) ¿Cómo nos fue en nuestro tercer año? Bueno, hacemos que valga la pena venir a la escuela cada día. Hacemos que los niños sientan que son importantes para nosotros. Hacemos que nuestro plan de estudios sea riguroso y relevante para ellos, y ellos usan toda la tecnología a la que están acostumbrados. Portátiles, computadoras, tabletas... lo que sea, lo tienen. Animación, programas para hacer películas, todo. Y conectamos todo a lo que están haciendo. Por ejemplo, hicieron anuncios de servicio público para la Sociedad del Cáncer que se anunciaron en el sistema de tranvías local. Enseñamos elementos de persuasión, no hay nada más real que eso. Nuestros resultados en las pruebas estatales han mejorado más de 80 puntos desde que nos convertimos en nuestra propia escuela. Pero todos los interesados han tenido que trabajar juntos: profesores y directores en contratos de un año, dedicando muchas más horas al trabajo que las del contrato sin compensación. Y se necesita un miembro del consejo escolar que vaya a presionar en nombre de uno y diga: "Sabes, el distrito trata de imponer esto, pero tienes la libertad de hacer otra cosa". Y se necesita un centro activo de padres de familia que no solo esté allí, mostrando su presencia a diario, sino que sea parte de nuestro gobierno, tomando decisiones por sus niños, nuestros niños. Porque, ¿por qué tienen los estudiantes que alejarse tanto de sus hogares? Se merecen una escuela de calidad en su barrio, una escuela a la que puedan sentirse orgullosos de asistir, y una escuela de la que también la comunidad pueda estar orgullosa, y los alumnos necesitan profesores que luchen por ellos a diario y les den el poder para sobreponerse a sus circunstancias. Porque es hora de que niños y niñas como yo dejen de ser la excepción, y sean la regla. Gracias. (Aplausos)